At the Croc, the Nessus kids play basketball while see on lines in yoga, and on the way
home, they always share tips.
That's why the Rodriguez family is famous around town for shooting hoops upside down.
They can dunk from downward dog, score three pointers from crow pose, and make hook shots
in headstands.
With so many activities, programs, and classes at the Croc, you never know what you'll get
into.
Join more than a gym when you click the link.
The Croc.
Get into it!
Minds are like parachutes, in that they function best when they're able to be opened.
And that is the thought for today.
Welcome to 7 Good Minutes.
I'm Clyde Lee Dennis.
Thanks for joining me for what I believe will be 7th of the most enriching minutes of your
day.
In today's episode of 7 Good Minutes, we hear about what makes a good student a good student.
Enjoy.
Today, we're going to learn about why C students are more successful than A students.
Now let's begin.
Number 1.
Innovative Thinking.
Many of the most successful people didn't stand because of their fantastic grades or
because of their prestigious degrees.
They made a name for themselves by thinking differently, by pioneering an idea that brought
something new to the table.
This is one huge reason why C students are more successful than A students.
They're more innovative thinkers.
They may not excel at writing essays, taking notes during lectures or memorizing information
from a textbook, but that's because the average student doesn't always fit the cookie-cutter
mold of what a smart person looks like.
Instead, they're more creative and inventive.
They learn to be clever in a way that school could never teach you.
That's why innovative thinking is such an incredibly common trait among the top 1% of
successful people.
Some of them attended respected universities and earned expensive degrees, but for other
successful people, school didn't really do much for them.
To get where they are today, they used their creative problem solving and their active
imagination.
Their innovative brain carried them to the top of the socio-economic food chain.
So don't let anyone tell you that good grades are the only way to find success.
The real secret has nothing to do with what letters are on your transcript.
Number 2.
Fearless Risk Takers
See students are not afraid to take risks.
They're not intimidated by failure or worried about looking bad, because they don't expect
everything to go perfectly.
That's where many straight A students fall short.
For over a decade, they've learned one thing.
Working hard will get you anything you want.
If you do everything you're supposed to do, then success will always follow.
But that's not how real life works.
You can try your absolute hardest, you can pour your blood, sweat and tears into a project,
and it can still fail miserably.
In fact, you might spend years failing at the same thing over and over again.
But see students, don't mind the ups and downs.
While a great student might give up after their first rough patch, an average student
knows what it means to struggle.
They know how to persevere through hardship and bad luck.
So when life knocks them down, C students are usually the first ones to get back up.
Number 3.
Resume Dependent
Some of the best students let their grades define them.
Instead of searching for their own passions, these students let their achievements replace
their entire personality.
It's almost like their whole life becomes one big resume, and everything they do, they
do to make themselves look better on paper.
This resume dependent mindset affects everything, their job, their friends, and even their lifestyle.
Because they're always thinking about how other people see them.
Back in school, they were rewarded for being as impressive as possible.
After graduation, whether they like it or not, that mentality will stick around.
On the other hand, C students don't care as much about impressing the rest of the world.
They're not worried about other people's expectations, because no one was expecting
as many amazing things from them.
Their parents and teachers probably weren't telling them to go to Ivy League schools,
or that they're destined for lifelong success.
So they learned how to satisfy themselves before anyone else.
And in the long run, that's what every successful person should be doing.
Number 4.
Means to an End
In the mind of a straight A student, education may seem like the end-all be-all.
It feels like an essential stepping stone toward your future.
But many average students think school is just a means to an end.
People like Bill Gates and Mark Zuckerberg dropped out of college for that exact reason.
They realized that school wasn't automatically going to make them successful.
In retrospect, they could have graduated, they could have handled the workload, but by
spending more time in class or doing homework, they were holding themselves back.
Yeah, I know it sounds weird to say, but school was a waste of their time.
So they quit.
Gates and Zuckerberg poured themselves into their passion projects, and they found success
by having faith in their own ability.
Many other average students and dropouts have followed in their footsteps, leaving school
to pursue success on their own.
They took that leap and left their education behind.
They bet everything on themselves, and for many of them, it actually worked.
5.
Following the Rules
School is full of rules.
Bells tell you when to eat.
Schedules tell you where to go, and teachers tell you what to learn.
So it's no surprise that straight A students are graded following the rules.
In fact, they thrive in strict and disciplined environments.
Love average students do what they're told and rarely question authority, which can get
them pretty far in life, but it can also slow them down.
If you spend your whole life walking on the beaten path, then you'll never discover what's
waiting for you out there in the wilderness.
And that's exactly what average students do.
They don't mind breaking the rules.
They don't like being bossed around or trapped inside a box.
Sometimes that makes these students rebellious and hard to control, but on your path toward
success.
That's a good thing.
They're often some of the boldest and bravest achievers because they don't follow anyone's
rules but their own.
Please keep in mind, this is about half of the entire presentation.
If you're up for a treat, you should definitely listen to the whole thing.
You can do so by clicking the link labeled "View the full video on YouTube in the show
notes."
So that does it for this episode of 7 Good Minutes.
Until next time, let's be civil to one another out there.
Thanks for listening.
(upbeat music)
(mellow music)